原创字幕: 人人影视
YYeTs.com
时间轴：wsr
你回来了
You're back.
想给你看看你做的好事...
Wanted to show you what you've done...
并亲自感谢你
...and to thank you in person.
这就是你做的
You did this!
看看我
Look at me!
亚蕾克西  看看你做了什么
Lexi, look what you've done!
陨落星辰
第四季 第十集
他在干嘛  接生吗
What's he doing -- delivering a baby?
既然知道怎么开车
Well, we learned how to start the car.
现在就要搞清楚怎么发动这玩意儿
Now we got to figure out how to drive the damn thing.
算了吧
Ah, forget it.
我们一直在这飞船上找转向装置
Been looking all over this damn ship for the steering mechanism.
连横舵柄都找不到
Can't even find the damn yoke.
也许根本没有
Perhaps there isn't one.
激光飞船是靠无线电波远程控制的
We know that Beamers are remote controlled by radio waves.
这种是无人机
They're drones.
我们得想办法超越远程控制
We must somehow override the remote control
对导航系统进行内部控制
and take local dominion of the navigation system.
没有横舵柄和方向盘  我们要怎么做
How do we do that if there's no yoke, no steering wheel?
跟我来  我给你们看一样东西
Come. Allow me to show you something.
别乱动  很危险
Hey, don't touch anything. It's dangerous.
你们也动了啊
You guys are touching stuff.
我们要搞明白怎么驾驶它
Well, we're trying to figure out how to fly it.
我也是
So am I.
你什么时候进入的青少年叛逆期
When did you enter your teenage rebellion phase?
当我成为青少年的时候
When I became a teenager.
这艘飞船把我的手臂刺得好疼
This ship stung the crap out of my arm, and it hurt.
我只是想给你点建议
I'm just trying to give you a little bit of advice.
我不需要建议
I don't need advice.
好吧  那我就不啰嗦了
Okay. Good talk.
要我看什么
What am I looking at?
找到月亮
Find the moon.
往下5度再看
Look 5 degrees below it.
一队激光飞船
A whole line of Beamers.
它们在跟随归航信标飞向艾士芬尼基地
They are following the homing beacon to the Espheni base.
也许我可以用替代通讯器
Perhaps I can use the sub communicator
来模仿艾士芬尼的归航信标
to mimic the Espheni homing beacon
欺骗这艘飞船  让它自行飞向月球
and trick the ship into flying to the moon on its own.
你觉得你可以黑入无人机
You think you can hack into the drone
然后让它起飞吗
and just go along for the ride?
-甚至都没必要找到方向盘  -正是
- We don't even need to find the steering wheel. - Precisely.
你可以黑进去吗
You think you can hack into it?
沃尔姆以前
The Volm have infiltrated
就侵入并控制过艾士芬尼自动飞船
and taken control of automated Espheni ships before.
我觉得可能性约百分之三十
I will give it one chance in three.
好吧
All right.
马特呢  他肯定又进去了
Where's Matt? He must've gone back in.
如果他还活着  我要杀了他
If he's still alive, I'm gonna kill him.
他才13岁
Hey, he's 13 years old.
我们也会做同样的事  别对他太苛刻
Remember, we would've done the same thing. Go easy on him.
我不是告诉过你什么也别碰
Hey! I thought I told you not to touch anything!
你为什么总是怒气冲冲的
Why do you have to always be so mad?
我想明白了
Look. I figured something out.
怎么了  马特  你做了什么
What is this, Matt? What'd you do?
推动了楼梯下的一个灯
Pushed one of the lights under the stairs
舱口就打开了
and the hatch popped open.
你碰了哪根触须之后飞船动了
Which tendrils did you touch to make the ship move?
看着
Look.
这根还有那根
This one and that one.
-你拉了这根  然后飞船就动了  -是啊
- You pull this, and the wings move? - Yeah.
拉吧
Pitch.
偏航肯定在附近  这两个控制是整合在一起的
Yaw must be nearby. The two controls are integrated.
瞧瞧  触须都集中在这一段了
See how the tendrils come together at the trunk here.
看见了吗  爸爸  现在我们知道如何控制飞船了
See, dad? Now we know how to control pitch.
有时候艾士芬尼
Sometimes the Espheni
把它们的联络通道隐藏在地面光谱中
try to hide their communication channels in the terrestrial spectrum.
是啊
Right.
等等  那是什么
Wait. What was that?
大家都听到了吗
Everybody hear that?
你们听到了吗  后退
Did you guys hear that? Go back.
那是西班牙语吗
Is that Spanish?
-说西班牙语  -安东尼  他在说什么
- Hablo Espanol. - Anthony, what's he saying?
宇宙中最普遍的力量是什么
What is the most pervasive force in the universe?
引力  一个物体对另一个物体的吸引力
Gravity -- the attraction of a body to another body.
就是引力让行星围绕太阳旋转
It's what makes the planets go around the suns.
宇宙也是同理
It's what makes the stars.
你天生就有独特的能力
And you have been born with the unique ability
能使用并控制引力和其它自然力量
to use gravity and other natural forces, to control them.
开发你的潜力  你就能做出了不起的事
As you develop your power, you will do amazing things.
你看见远处的那些树吗
Do you see those trees in the distance?
那颗高高的树
The tall one.
那颗大橡树
The big, live oak.
我想让你打破引力
I want you to break the chains of graviy
并将其结合在一起
that hold it together.
我不想毁掉它
I don't want to destroy it.
这不是毁掉它
You aren't destroying it.
而是释放它  让它回宇宙
You are setting it free, sending it back to the stars.
你是和平使者
You are the bringer of peace.
你能感受到树的每个原子
Can you feel every atom of the tree
拉扯着另一个原子
pulling on every other atom,
而世界上其它的原子
and all the other atoms in the world
拉扯着那些原子吗
pulling on those atoms?
这就是宇宙永恒的激烈竞争
That is the eternal tug-of-war of the universe.
我想让你
I want you to take
使用不间断的静态力量
all that relentless static background power
逆转它
and reverse it.
将引力转换为推力
Turn the pull into a push.
使用你头脑中的光
Use the light in your mind.
天赋异禀
Singularly gifted.
我没法呼吸了
I can't breathe.
歇会儿吧
Rest.
你的力量会回来的  而且更为强大
Your strength will come back, stronger next time.
我能变得多强大
How strong can I get?
这取决于你在训练中有多刻苦
It depends on how disciplined you are in your training.
你的潜力无限
Your potential is unlimited.
我能制造出星星吗
Could I make a star?
你完善后的力量会是非凡的
Your perfected power will be...divine.
我们从激光飞船内部收到了无线电广播
We received a radio transmission from inside the Beamer.
那是循环程序  一直在播那一段消息
Yeah, it was a loop -- the same message over and over.
"集中营被清空了
"The ghettos are being emptied.
安达卢西亚几乎无人幸存
Almost no one is left in Andalusia.
意大利和摩洛哥也是如此
It is the same in Italy and Morocco.
所有人都被送去转化了
Virtually everyone has been taken for processing.
敌人有了新武器  来捕捉人类逃亡者
The enemy has a new weapon to capture human fugitives.
我见过  很恐怖
I've seen it. It's horrific,
比我们之前碰到的一切武器更强大
beyond anything we have encountered before.
相信我  我们无力抵抗
Believe me when I say there is no defense.
任何听到这条信息的人应该明白
Anyone hearing this should realize
你们是人类的最后幸存者
you are one of the last remaining pockets of humanity.
不要试图反抗
Do not attempt to fight back.
转入地下
Go to ground...
撤退
Retreat...
躲藏
hide...
生存下去
survive...
不然这就是人类的末日"
Or this is the end."
我们怎么知道这是真的
How do we know this is real,
而不是艾士芬尼的另一个圈套
not just another Espheni trick?
不知道  这条消息是在
We don't. But it was broadcast on a frequency
我们的频率上进行广播的
that we think was ours.
那是什么频率
What frequency is that?
1776兆赫  美国独立的年份
1776 megahertz, as in American Independence.
有人在找我们  希望我们收到消息
Somebody's looking out for us, hoping we'd get the code.
那我们要怎么做
So, what are we gonna do?
那声音说我们需要撤退躲藏生存下去
Those voices said we need to retreat, hide, survive.
可我们没地方躲了
We're kind of running out of places to do that.
要离开这里吗
We just gonna leave here?
是啊  我们要去解放其它集中营
Yeah, we're gonna go liberate another ghetto,
把人们救出来  在...
get some people out of there before...
在什么之前
Before what?
艾士芬尼的方案正在进行中
The Espheni solution is happening.
我亲眼所见
I've seen it for myself.
这听起来像是另一个
Well, it sounds like yet another
"守住阵地"的方法
"hold down the fort" detail to me,
而我个人绝对无意于
and I, for one, have no intention
再次坐以待毙
of playing the sitting-duck card again.
玛吉说得对
Maggie's right, all right?
集合招募一些新人有什么不对
What's wrong with rounding up some new recruits, huh?
我们壮大队伍  离开这里
We replenish the army, we get out there,
干掉那些蟑螂
and we frag those cockroaches, huh?
如果那广播说的是真事
'Cause if that broadcast is telling the truth
转化进展到这种地步了
and this mutation process is that far along,
我们必须更积极地应对
we need to do something even more aggressive than that.
抱歉  我忘了你的终极规划
Sorry, I forgot your master plan --
要劫持外面的千年隼号
Hijack the, uh, Millennium Falcon out there
然后飞向月球
and fly it to the moon.
珀普  闭嘴
Pope, shut up.
我还没听到更好的计划  至少你没说出来
Haven't heard a better plan yet. Not out of you, anyway.
我们没法赢得消耗战  我们没有人手
We can't win a war of attrition. We don't have the numbers.
我们要进行的也许不是最理性的计划
What we are about to embark on may not be the most rational plan,
但我相信这是最可能成功的计划
but I do believe that it is the plan with the best chance of success.
如果我们没时间了  也许这太绝望了
If we've run out of time, maybe this is too desperate.
也许我们该躲起来
Maybe we should just hide.
就我个人而言  我不会躲起来
Okay, I'm just gonna speak for myself. I'm not gonna hide.
我受够了四处觅食  行尸走肉一般活下去
I'm sick of scrounging around and just surviving.
我肯定我们能找到一个洞穴  可以维持
I'm sure we could find a cave, and we could eke out
一周  一个月或者一年
another week or another month, another year,
但...  我更想赢得战争
but that -- I want to win the war.
如果有办法  如果有任何办法
And if there's a way -- if there is any way
削弱艾士芬尼的能量核
that we can cripple the Espheni power core,
打倒它们的战争防御
we can bring down their war defenses,
我一定会照做
then that's what I'm gonna do.
汤姆说得对  这样活不下去
Tom's right. This is no way to live.
你觉得谁会那么愚蠢
And exactly who do you propose would be foolish enough
驾驶那个飞碟飞向月球
to pilot that flying saucer to the moon?
我
Me.
我觉得你太轻率了
I just think you're being rash.
你在机械地应对局势
You're treating this situation by rote,
如果这只是另一个...
if it's just another --
我没有机械应对
There's nothing rote about it.
是我在推动计划  我得付诸行动
I'm the one driving the plan. I have to walk the walk.
我很高兴你这样做
And I'm glad you are.
-大家都是  -但是呢
- Everyone is. - But?
但你不能再次做出单方决定
But you can't make another unilateral decision
就因为这是两点之间最短的距离
just because it's the shortest distance between two points.
根本没有好选择
There are no good options here.
我知道  而且我明白你担心
I mean, I see that, and I know that you're worried.
我不仅仅是担心
It's more than that I'm just worried.
你要驾驶着外星人飞船飞向月球了  汤姆
I mean, you are flying on an alien spaceship to the moon, Tom.
想想吧
A-and just think about it.
你摧毁了能量核后
Once you destroy the power core,
那不就能毁灭一切艾士芬尼驱动的东西吗
doesn't that kill everything Espheni-powered?
你打算怎么回来呢
How the hell are you planning on getting back, exactly?
科奇斯研究过了
Cochise has done his homework.
他说激光飞船中应该储存有足够的能量
He says there should be enough stored power in the Beamer
能飞回地球  像电池之类的东西
to fly it home, in a -- like, a battery or something.
那还真是令人欣慰啊
Oh. Well, that's -- that's reassuring.
好吧  一旦地球上的艾士芬尼
Okay, well, once the Espheni here on earth
意识到自己惨遭重创
realize that they've been hit hard,
你觉得它们不会报复吗
you think they're not gonna retaliate?
你不觉得它们报复的时候
And don't you think we need you here
-我们需要你在这里吗  -这是两个人的工作
- alive when they do? - It's a two-man job.
科奇斯驾驶  我来部署炸弹
Cochise pilots, and I have to deploy the bombs.
但我没法让别人去做
Hey, but I can't ask somebody else to do this.
我要身先士卒
And I need to lead by example.
可以  但先要得到你领导的人们的同意
I want you to lead, but with the consent of those you're leading.
汤姆  你得认真想想
Tom, you've got to think it through
让你身边的人和你一起想清楚
and allow the people around you to think it through with you.
我们成功的唯一方法
That is the only way we pull this off --
就是大家一起做决定
if we decide things together.
我明白你的意思  真的
I hear what you're saying, I really do,
我知道你说的不止是团队
and I know you're not just talking about the group.
我们现在是搭档
We are -- we are partners now.
-是啊  -你明白吗
- Yeah. - You got me?
我明白
Yeah, I got you. I do.
好吧
Okay.
打扰了
Uh, excuse me.
没事  怎么了
It's okay. What's up?
我们需要你来一下激光飞船
We need you at the beamer.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们正在干活儿  突然间
We were working, and all of a sudden,
从激光飞船的控制台伸出了这些触须
these tendrils lurched out of the beamer console
缠住了沃尔姆通讯器
and seized the Volm communicator.
然后烧焦了它
And fried it.
这是因为我们在使用沃尔姆科技
It is because we integrated the Volm technology
来登录飞船的航行系统
in order to access the ship's navigation system.
显然  激光飞船配备有防御机制
Apparently, this beamer is armed with a defense mechanism
发现了沃尔姆的覆盖命令
which recognized the Volm override.
我担心等飞船完全激活后
Once this ship is fully activated,
发现任何沃尔姆的存在
I worry it will recognize any Volm presence
也将会拒绝执行我的命令
and will reject me.
你是说你不能参与这个任务了吗
You're saying you can't go on the mission?
我是可以的  但是
I could, but...
我的参加会导致计划失败
it would jeopardize our objective.
所以我们之中的唯一一个
So, the only one of us who has any understanding
了解这东西怎么运作的人不能参加
of how this thing works is grounded.
看来这便车搭不成了
So much for hitching a ride.
还是有一个机会的
There is... one possibility.
如果能在人工操作下让它
If we can manage to fly this beamer manually
升出地球大气的干扰
above the interference of Earth's atmosphere,
它有可能可以自动锁定
there is a chance it will automatically lock onto
归航信标  返回艾士芬尼能量核
the homing beacon to the Espheni power core.
-然后自动飞向月球  -是的
- And then fly itself to the moon? - Yes.
所以它不是个魔毯  它是架飞机
So it's not a magic carpet, it's an airplane?
飞机有四种基本操作
Airplanes have four basic controls --
推力  俯仰  偏航  横滚
thrust, pitch, yaw, roll.
我们已经会俯仰和偏航  多亏了你儿子
And we already know pitch and yaw, thanks to your son.
而且也知道控制面板在哪儿  多亏了你儿子
And we know where the main control panel is, thanks to your son.
现在我们只需找到控制推力和横滚的方法了
So, then, all we need to isolate is thrust and roll...
就用老办法来吧
the old-fashioned way.
开始
Pull!
没反应
Nothing.
开始
Pull!
没反应
Nothing.
开始
Pull!
停下  停下
Stop! stop! stop!
科奇斯差点就被吸入进气道了
Cochise nearly got sucked through the intake.
推力找到了
Thrust.
开始
Pull.
炸弹做的怎么样了
How's the bomb coming?
我说  炸弹做的怎么样了
I said, um, how's the bomb coming?
如果没办法控制催化剂
Well, if we can't figure out a way to control this accelerant,
就很难把握爆炸的时机
it's gonna be hard to time the explosion.
我...
Look, um...
我知道我越界了
I know I crossed the line.
什么界啊
And what line is that --
追你哥哥的女友时
the line you don't cross
还有什么界限可言吗
when you're hitting on your brother's girlfriend?
你要理解  我们没法控制此事
You have to understand, it -- we couldn't help it.
这是刺钉的作用
S-something's going on with the spikes.
原来是刺钉啊  好吧
Spikes. Right.
你怎么知道不是因为你就是爱上了她
How do you know you don't just like her?
我和玛吉本来不会有任何关系  要不是...
I wouldn't have done anything with Maggie if it wasn't...
你是我哥哥  哈尔
You're my brother, Hal.
我绝不会有意伤害你
I'd n-never do anything to hurt you.
说得容易
That's easy to say, isn't it?
我们还没找到横滚的机制  但一定能的
We haven't isolated the roll mechanism just yet, but we will.
可能性太多了
There are so many options.
什么时候能试飞呢
When can we take it for a test drive?
我不知道试飞能不能直接就...
I doubt we'll be able to take it for a test drive before --
可我们并不是要精准的降落在航空母舰上
Well, remember, we don't have to land on a navy carrier.
我们要做的只是让它升空
I mean, all we have to do is fly up.
可以说目标就是天空
The sky is literally the target.
根据科奇斯的判断结论
According to Cochise's diagnostics,
一旦进入太空
once in space,
激光飞船就能锁定艾士芬尼归航信标
the beamer will lock onto the Espheni homing beacon
自动飞向月球基地
and fly to the moon base on its own.
但我们还是得做些基本训练
We still need to train with it.
至少需要两个人丢炸弹
I mean, it's gonna take two people to drop the bomb.
我来驾驶  然后...
I can pilot it --
等等  这事还没定吧  伙计
Whoa. Uh, has that been decided yet, partner?
当然定了  他一直都爱抢功
Of course it has. He's a glory hog.
等等  我想重点不在于功劳吧
Hold on. I realize it's not about that.
但是汤姆
But, Tom...
至少这个任务是独一无二的
this task is unique, to say the least.
这并不是一次救援或者夺取武器的任务
It's not just another rescue mission or weapons grab.
这事是要永载史册的
This is for all the marbles.
不应该至少
Shouldn't there be...
有个更公平的决策过程吗
a fair process to determine how it works?
听起来不错
Sounds good.
我同意
I agree.
我们应该抽签以示公平
We should draw straws to be fair.
这话居然是个孩子说的
Out of the mouths of babes.
而且我觉得不错
Sounds like a good idea to me.
抽签  开玩笑吗
Draw straws? Are you joking?
这不是游戏
This isn't a game.
我们要的是合适的人选
We should pick the right person for the job.
那谁说你就是那个合适人选了呢
Exactly who said that you were the best person for the job?
我有13小时的飞行经历  你有吗
I have 13 registered hours as a pilot. Do you?
-我喜欢这个方法  -听起来不错
- I like it. - Sounds pretty good.
-我也想试试  -你有...
- I want to take a shot. - You got something --
-嘿  -我也想干这事
- Hey... - I want to do it.
我觉得这事不能凭运气决定
I don't think any of this should be left to chance.
那你可以反对抽签
Then you can vote against the draw.
同意的举手
Who's for it?
好吧  我们抽签
Okay, we'll draw straws.
这是个很危险的任务
It's a very dangerous mission.
谁也不能被迫参加  报名必须是自愿的
Nobody should be forced to go. Draw should be voluntary.
我要说一句  大家都要
I tell you what -- think very carefully
谨慎考虑要不要自愿报名
whether or not you want to volunteer.
如果愿意  待会儿再回来
If you do come back later.
我们会在这儿放纸笔
We'll get pen, paper.
写下你的名字  放进来  晚上再开会
Write your names out. Put them in here. Come back tonight.
然后我们抽签 看看谁是这个幸运儿
We'll pull out the names, find out who got lucky.
-我为你骄傲  -骄傲什么
- I'm proud of you. - For what?
骄傲你同意抽签  这是个很民主的决定
For going with the draw. It was very democratic of you.
也调动了很大的积极性
I also think it got everyone more invested.
我已经报名了
I already put my name in.
我觉得这是个糟糕透顶的办法
I think it's a horrible idea.
我觉得我们应该
I think we should go with the person
-让最有可能成功的人去  -是你
- who's got the most chance of success... - Meaning you.
而不是随机挑选出来的人
... not just pick people at random.
顺便问句  如果哈尔或本被选中怎么办
By the way, what happens if Hal or Ben gets picked?
我会郁闷  但我们不能随便破例
I would hate that, but we can't make exceptions
-就因为...  -因为他们是我的孩子吗
- just because... - Because they're my children?
我们难道不是一家人吗
Aren't we all a family now?
是  很抱歉我说了这样的话
Yeah. I'm sorry I said that.
不过结果如何你不能反悔吧
Look, you're gonna accept the results, right?
你不能用你的权力改变人选吧
You're not gonna pull rank if you don't like who gets decided?
我真的不知道如果被选中的人
I honestly don't know how I would react
是我的儿子我会作何反应
if one of the boys gets picked.
我和你一样
I'm on your side.
不是只有你能拯救世界  汤姆
You're not the only one who can save the world, Tom.
我想报名
I want to put my name in the draw.
不行  你才13岁
No. You're 13.
你说过圣女贞德想要为她的国家而战时
You said Joan of Arc was a teenager when
也才十几岁而已
she wanted to fight for her country.
-别跟我贫嘴  -抽签还是我的意见呢
- Don't get smart with me right now, please. - The draw was my idea!
我知道  但是15岁以上
Yeah, I know, but you have to be 15
才能驾驶外星飞船
to pilot an alien spaceship,
你连驾照都没有呢
and you don't have your learner's permit yet.
-真是的  -没什么好说的了
- God! - End of discussion.
我很担心这孩子呢
Worried about that kid.
你想谈谈混血的事吗  兄弟
You wanted to discuss the hybrid, brother.
我担心不久你就无法掌控她了
I'm worried you won't be able to control her for much longer.
不用担心  她完全效忠于我们
Don't be. She's completey committed to our cause.
她完全效忠于我们
She's completely committed to our cause.
她更趋近于人类而不是艾士芬尼
She's more human than Espheni.
她认为人类是低级物种  像我们教的那样
She sees humanity as inferio, as she has been taught.
你也看见了她对那棵树所做的事
You saw what she did to the forest.
正是因为那件事我才召唤你
That's the reason I summoned you.
她的进步之快
She's progressing much more quickly
超乎我的想象
than I could've imagine.
凭她一己之力就能帮我们赢得战争
She could single-handedy win us the war.
但如果她背叛  我们就会输
Or lose it if she rebels.
她不会背叛的
She's not going to rebel.
而且就算她背叛了
And even if she did,
我还有特殊的方法控制她
I have a special means to control her.
相信我  她不知道我们要用她干什么
Trust me -- she has no idea of our purpose for her.
她以为她的能力是以带来和平为目的
She thinks her power is being developed for peace.
我不在乎  结束它
I don't care. End it.
我要你消除她所带来的隐患
I want you to eliminate the risk she represents.
你想要我杀了她吗
You want me to kill she?
这是最保险的方式
That's the safest course of action.
按我说的去做  结束她
Now do as I say. End her.
好的  兄弟
Yes, brother.
我报名时看见你也把名字放进去了
I saw you put your name in the draw when I put mine in.
这是最好的决定
It's the right thing to do.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
字面意思
Just that.
我想做正确的事...
I try to do the right thing...
为了我的家人...
for my family...
和我爱的人
the people I care about.
我也是
So do I.
我看见你和本的事了
I saw you with Ben.
对不起  哈尔
I'm so sorry, Hal.
这...
It's --
本和我因为刺钉联系在了一起
Ben and I have this connection because of the spikes.
这完全是生理反应  我...
It's more physical than anything else. I --
我不知道该怎么解释
I don't know how to explain it.
我已经知道了
You know, I've already heard this story, and, um...
而且我也理解
You know what? I get it.
也许你们俩是天生一对
You know, maybe the two of you are meant for each other.
不  我不是这个意思
No. That's not what I'm saying.
当我和本距离很近时
When Ben and I are near each other,
就有一种像是被刺钉链接起来了的感觉
it's like the spikes are attracted to each other.
这不是我们能控制的
It's totally out of our control.
你们俩可以把
You know, it's just so convenient
没有自控力的责任推卸给刺钉
that you both have these spikes
真是方便极了
that you can blame for your lack of self-control.
也许你还不知道
I got news for you.
但每个人都对刺钉有自己的看法
Everybody's got their version of spikes.
我的看法是  这叫心心相惜
"Heart wants what it wants."
可我并不想和本在一起
I don't want to be with Ben.
这才是我想说的
That's what I'm saying.
你知道吗  事实是...
You know, the truth is...
你伤害了我
you just really hurt me.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我早该知道的
I should've known you --
你反悔了
you'd try to get out of it.
放了名字然后溜回来想取出来  对吗
Put your name in and sneak back and take it out, see?
你知道你这种人叫什么吗
There's a word for people like you.
什么啊  懦夫吗
Yeah, what's that? Coward?
拜托  提出我们应该站起来
Please. I'm the one saying we should get off our ass,
召集人们拿上武器
round up some men and some weapons,
去屠杀这些外星害虫的人就是我
and frag these cockroaches.
那就别抱怨去做事
Yeah, why don't you quit complaining and go do that?
我也想  但我一个人做不到
I would. But I can't -- not alone.
梅森给大家都洗脑了
Mason's got everybody so brainwashed --
是这样啊
Is that what it is?
你总是有各种借口  珀普
You never run out of excuses, do you, Pope?
怎么  就因为我不想
Why, because I don't see the point
浪费时间在毫无希望的赌局上吗
in wasting nothing but time on a wing and a prayer?
就算他们真能启动那个激光飞船
You know, even if they get that beamer running,
它也一定会坠毁
it's gonna crash.
与此同时  我们这些剩下的人
Meanwhile, the rest of us -- see, we're all sitting
还无所事事的坐在这里成为靶子
in one place with a giant target on our heads!
走着瞧吧
You watch.
这个小冒险
This little "adventure,"
会和所有冒险一个下场
it's gonna end like they all end --
那就是失败
with a smudge on a windshield.
我们不过是小白鼠  上尉  在等着
We're all just a bunch of lab rats, Cap, just waiting...
看它们下次又能想出什么样的
for whatever delightful little Skitter experiment
迅猎兽实验
they're brewing up next.
不过  你应该早就懂了的吧
Then again, you'd probably know all about that,
不是吗
now, wouldn't you?
我没有把我的名签从颅骨里拿出来
I didn't take my name out of the skull!
I didn't take my name out of the skull.
我亲眼看见你这么干了
I just saw you do it!
我拿的不是我的  是你的
It wasn't my name. It was yours...
你和梅森的
yours and Mason's.
什么
What?
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
给我拿来
Give me that.
我要开那艘飞船
I need to be on that ship.
行了吧  我想被选中
All right? I need to be chosen.
听着
Look --
这些人
these people, they...
他们需要你
they need you...
需要你和梅森  没人需要我
you and Mason. Nobody needs me.
如果我明天失踪了
I could disappear tomorrow,
可能都没人会注意到
I really doubt that anybody's gonna notice, all right?
我一定要上那艘激光飞船上
I got to be on that ship.
它是有去无回的  对吧
That Beamer's on a one-way ticket, all right?
它不会回来了  我们都知道
It ain't coming back, and we both know that.
让我...
Let me be...
让我来做这个英雄吧  丹
let me be the hero, Dan.
让我来做殉道者
Let me be the martyr.
好吗
Right?
这次任务  能够造福全人类
The mission's just -- just a Hail-Mary for the planet, man.
让我...
Let me do...
做点...做点...
something -- something --
能流芳百世的事吧
something worth remembering.
你是说  这对你来说
So you're saying that, for you,
是一种解脱
this is just another way out.
如果是呢
So what if it is?
你是认真的吗  珀普
Are you serious, Pope?
我不想继续了  不想战斗  不想逃跑
I'm done. I'm done fighting. I'm done running.
我什么都不想干了
I'm done with the whole program.
梅森在这件事上是对的
Mason's right about one thing.
我们...
This is...
我们活不下去  也不值得活下去了
this is no way to live. This life is not worth living.
况且我有什么
And what do I got?
没有家人  没有...
I got no family. I got...
没有老婆孩子
I got no kids, no wife.
一无所有
I got nothing, man.
她可能会回来的
She might come back.
起来吧
Come on.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我承认错误
I-I stand corrected.
我以为...
I thought...
我知道你是怎么想的
I know what you thought.
能让我来吗
Mind if I do the honors?
请吧
Go ahead.
这里有很多名字
Lot of names in here.
天哪  有谁没把自己的名字放进去吗
Boy, did anybody not put their name?
意义很大
That says a lot.
谢谢你们
Thank you.
好了
Okay.
被选中的是...
The winner is...
本
Ben.
加油  孩子
Way to go, kid.
-我支持你  孩子  -加油  本
- I got your back, kid. - Way to go, Ben.
这是一个
Well, that's one.
另一个是谁
Who's the other?
是我
It's me.
我能看看吗
May I?
看来是我俩了  我们能成功
Looks like it's you and me. We got this.
是的  我们能成功
Yeah, we got this.
费了这么大劲  还是他被选中了
Well, after all of that... he gets picked anyway.
真是经典
Now, that is classic.
一家人中选中了两个
Two from one family.
事已至此
That's the way the cookie crumbles.
在出发之前我有很多事要做  所以...
I got a lot to do before I go, so...
汤姆
Tom...
你能先坐下吗
will you sit down?
拜托
Please?
你有没有那么做
Did you or didn't you?
有没有做什么
Did I or didn't I what?
作弊
Fix the draw?
这可能是我们最后一次在一起
This might be the last time we're together.
你就想这么离开我们吗
Is this really how you want to leave us?
-你是不是把它放在手中  -是的
- Did you palm it? - Yeah.
我作弊了
I fixed it.
你是懂历史的
You know history.
这就是那种导致失败的狂妄自大
This is exactly the kind of hubris that comes before the fall.
如果被人发现了
If people found out,
会毁掉人们对你作为领袖的信任
it would destroy their trust in your leadership.
会毁掉一切我们为之抗争的事
It would jeopardize everything we've been fighting for.
你真的愿意冒这么大的风险吗
Are you really willing to risk all of that?
我不会让本自己去的
I'm not willing to let Ben go without me.
但不仅仅是因为这个  我有种感觉
But even more than that, I just have this feeling
就好像我应该参加这次任务似的
like I'm supposed to go on this mission.
我想不出该怎么描述这种感觉
I can't even think of any other way to describe it
反正我就是这么觉得
except I just have this sense.
这就是我应该做的
This is what I'm supposed to do.
就像你对亚蕾克西的信念一样
It's like your belief in Lexi.
准备好训练了吗
Are you ready to train?
是的  父亲
Yes, father.
闭上你的眼睛
Close your eyes.
放松
Relax.
-用...  -我心中的光
- Use the... - The light in my mind.
是的  没错
Yes. That's right.
我一直在练习
I've been practicing.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
我是带来和平的人  还记得吧
I'm the bringer of peace, remember?
我听到了你们兄弟在阴影位面的对话
I heard your conversation with your brother in the shadow plane.
我带来的根本不是和平
I'm not the bringer of peace at all.
而是死亡
I'm the bringer of death.
有一件事你说对了
You were right about one thing.
完善后的能力是非凡的
Power perfected is divine.
说实话
Got to be honest --
我希望是我跟你一起去
I wish I was the one going up there with you.
据说在月球上能把高尔夫球打出两英里外
They say you can hit a golf ball about two miles up there.
可是球进洞一定很难
Bet the putting's tough.
要开激光飞船了  你有什么感觉
How do you feel about flying the Beamer?
基本的控制我都会了
I got the basic controls down,
但在我们真正地出发之前
but until we go live, until we do it for real...
我也不确定
well, I don't know.
-只有做了才知道  -没错
- Nothing to it but to do it. - That's right.
我听说了你和本的事
So, I heard about you and Ben.
是吗  谁告诉你的
Yeah? Who told you?
本
Ben.
他说如果不是因为刺钉的话
He said none of this would've happened
这一切都不会发生
if it hadn't been for the spikes.
这就像说  如果不是因为艾士芬尼的话
You know, that's like saying the war wouldn't have happened
这场战争就不会发生
if it wasn't for the Espheni.
我不知道是不是跟刺钉有关
I don't know if it had anything to do with the spikes or not.
但我了解本  我了解他的性格
I do know Ben. I do know his character.
玛吉跟我说他们对彼此都有感觉
Maggie told me they both got feelings for each other.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
在历史上  这也不是第一次
You're not the first brothers in history
兄弟俩喜欢上同一个女孩了
to fall for the same girl.
而且  最终也不是由你或本来决定
And ultimately, it won't be up to you or Ben.
还是要由玛吉来决定
It'll be up to Maggie.
一开始是我坚持要给她移植刺钉的
I'm the one who pushed to give her those spikes in the first place.
他想见你
He wants to see you.
你应该去看看你弟弟
You should go see your brother.
-这可能是最后的机会了  -别这么说
- You might not get another chance. - Don't talk like that.
别让我这样说
Well, hey, don't make me feel like I have to.
我很害怕
This one has me scared.
我应该一开始就向你坦白
I should've told you everything from the beginning.
很抱歉我没有那么做  不会再有下次了
I'm sorry that I didn't. It won't happen again.
但你对作弊的事不后悔  是吧
But you're not sorry you fixed the draw, right?
是的
No.
我不会说出去
I won't tell.
我应该想得到
I should've known...
当他们说要抽签的时候
when they announced the draw,
你就能想出应对的办法
you'd find a way to go.
你是个好父亲
You're a good father.
我会尽一切努力回来找你
I'm gonna do everything that I can to come back to you.
我保证
I promise.
我有一个礼物要给你
I have a gift for you.
离别礼物
A going-away present?
不  是结婚纪念日第二天礼物
Nope. A second-day anniversary present.
是什么
What is it?
斯多葛学派哲学家爱比克泰德的书
Epictetus. The Stoic.
《一个人应该为自己做好充分的准备》
"A man should be prepared to be sufficient unto himself."
-这是我最喜欢的书之一  -我知道
- It's one of my favorites. - I know.
你在哪儿发现的
Where'd you find it?
在我们找你的时候  在一堆乱石中发现的
I found it in some rubble when we were digging for you.
被我注意到了  我就留着了
Caught my eye. I've been saving it.
谢谢
Thank you.
能装进口袋里  很适合要出门的人
It's pocket-sized. It's perfect for the man on the go.
你确定人要充分准备好吗
You sure a man should be sufficient unto himself?
爱比克泰德知道什么
What does Epictetus know?
怎么样了
How's it going?
炸弹已经装好了
Bomb's packed,
炸药在充电  检查了两遍导线
Set the tovex for the charge, double-checked the wiring.
连上计时器就行
Just got to connect the timer.
我是说你
I meant with you.
你一定很害怕  对吧
I mean, you must be scared, right?
-我或许不应该来这  -或许吧
- I probably shouldn't be here. - Probably.
我是想来道别
I just had to say goodbye.
我会想你的
I'm gonna miss you.
我  我不会去太长时间
I'm-- I won't be gone too long.
很快就回来了
I'll be back before you know it.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
我也会想你
I'm gonna miss you, too.
我们不应该
We shouldn't.
哈尔
Hal.
Hal...
我是来接受你的道歉的
I came to accept your apology.
-哈尔  -行了
- Hal... - Just...
别说了
just stop.
抱歉
Sorry.
哈尔
Hal!
最糟糕的道别
Worst goodbye ever.
好了  丁甘  我们应该都准备好了
Okay, Dingaan. Looks like we're all set.
对我们的飞行计划还有什么要说的吗
Any last thoughts on our flight plan?
记住  一旦进入高空大气
Remember, once you reach the upper atmosphere
你们就会知道  因为那时就能看到日冕了
you'll know it because you'll be able to see the corona.
在北面
Above the surface to the north.
那时我就应该打开信标
That's when I turn the beacon on.
你已经知道了
You have it.
谢谢你所做的一切  我的朋友
Thanks for everything, my friend.
-祝你好运  汤姆  -谢谢
- Good luck, Tom. - Thank you.
保护好我的家人
Keep my family safe.
一定  祝你成功
You got it. Godspeed.
帮我照顾好韦弗上校  好吗
Keep an eye on Colonel Weaver for me, would you?
你在哪儿  哈尔
Where are you, Hal?
马特  你要坚强
Matt, I'm counting on you to be strong.
别害怕自己的情绪波动
Don't be afraid to let yourself feel things.
知道  只是要坚强地克服它们
I feel things. Just got to be tough about them.
-你也不必总是坚强  -不  我要
- Well, you don't have to be so tough all the time. - Yes, you do.
老爸  我爱你
Dad, I love you.
我也爱你
I love you.
谢谢你
Thank you...
保护了我
for protecting me and for...
爱我
loving me and...
理解我
understanding me.
我会回来的
I shall return.
你当然要回来  你还欠我一次蜜月
Oh, you better. You owe me a honeymoon.
我一直在想
You know, I was thinking
昨晚发生的一切
about everything that happened last night,
我只是想告诉你  我原谅你了
And, I just want to let you know I forgive you.
我的确对玛吉有感觉
I do have feelings for Maggie.
抱歉  但我真的有
I'm sorry, but I do.
谢谢你的坦白
Well, thank you for coming clean.
别担心  她是因为刺钉的关系
Don't worry. For her, it's about the spikes.
我们还是别说这事了
Let's just not even talk about it, you know?
我觉得此时此刻不应该...
I don't think this is the time or the place...
谢谢你原谅我
Thanks for fogiving me.
也谢谢你没有揍我
And for not punching me.
事实是  我不能决定玛吉该做什么
You know, the truth of matter is I am not the one to tell Maggie what she can
或者不该做什么  所以...
or can't do, anyway, so...
这取决于她
it's up to her.
你说得对  这取决于她
You're right. It's up to her.
谁知道呢  再过几年
Who knows, man? Next couple of years,
说不定是马特娶了她
Matt will probably end up marrying her, anyway.
来吧
Come here.
照顾好老爸  知道吗
Hey, keep an eye on dad up there, all right?
-好的  -太好了
- Yeah. - Oh, good.
很高兴看到你们和好了
I'm glad to see you two made up.
一定要成功
Go get 'em.
等一下  等一下  别发射  停下
Wait! Wait! Stop the launch! Stop!
-怎么了  -我听到点东西
- What's the matter? - I hear something!
-是什么  -有东西来了
- The hell is it? - Something's coming.
快点  走  走
Come on! Move! Move!
激光飞船
Beamers!
找掩护
Take cover!
散开  散开  大家退后
Spread out! Spread out! Everybody, back!
退后  马特
Stand down, Matt!
把枪放下
Put that gun down.
蹲下
Stay down!
Get down.
小心  马特
Look out, Matt!
-怎么回事  -安全了
- What happened?! - All clear.
-它们在半空爆炸了  -什么
- They just blew up in midair. - What?!
谁干的
Who did that?
你好  父亲
Hello, father.